<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Nitemare Cafe</title><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/</link>
<description>A day in the life of a computer geek</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 12:23:37 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 12:23:37 -0500</pubDate>
<atom:link href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
Not retro enough...
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Since beginning to drive this site with <a href="https://github.com/cfenollosa/bashblog/tree/master">bashblog</a>,
 I have allowed a minor bit of bloat to creep back in. I do drive the site with a bit of css,
 but I have tried to keep the design fairly simply despite this so that the site renders
 perfectly fine using any low-powered (and even text-only) web browser.</p>

<p>A couple of features require the user to allow JavaScript. For a connection to <a href="/chat.html">Discord</a>,
 this is fine. It's a completely optional part of the site, and not in active use, so if you
 don't have JavaScript, no biggie. You're not really missing anything. But even though they
 are rarely used, I absolutely <b>have</b> to allow comments. Unless I go back to self-hosting
 (which is actually feasible again via <a href="/cloudflare.html">Cloudflare</a>),
 the only way to allow them was to connect to <a href="https://disqus.com/">Disqus</a>, which
 also requires JavaScript. This is not ideal, and I may be able to hack together a small bit
 of php to enable comments if I go back to self-hosting, but because comments rarely get used,
 I am not sure it is worth the effort of seeing them as more than an optional part of the site.</p>

<p>Also, there's the <a href="https://feeds.feedburner.com/wintermutesblog">Feedburner</a> version
 of <a href="/feed.rss">my feed</a>, which is again optional, and
 only enabled for the person or two who were using it to follow me. lol. The second link takes
 you to the actual feed. ;)</p>

<p>So, if you're able to comment (if not, feel free to email me at wintermute @ my domain),
 what do you think? Should I forgo the nicities and strip away the optional bloat? Should
 I leave it as-is, because it doesn't impede anyone's ability to follow the site?</p>

<p>As an aside, this post was partly inspired by one about <a href="https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/">rediscovering the small web</a>.
 I strongly suggest you go read that.</a>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_web.html'>web</a>, <a href='tag_retro.html'>retro</a></p>






<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/not-retro-enough.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/not-retro-enough.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./not-retro-enough.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 11:58:44 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
VoIP.ms
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Well, it finally happened. I got and installed replacement batteries for my <a href="/payphone.html">payphone</a>,
 but it still did not work completely. My OBI200 ATA finally quit working with Google Voice, as it has been end-of-support for some time
 now. I knew it was coming, but hadn't made a backup plan. So I found an inexpensive VoIP provider, <a href="http://voip.ms">VoIP.ms</a>,
 and managed to get it going fairly quickly. There are walkthroughs for configuring a ton of different devices, so a quick factory-reset
 of the OBI and following a quick guide, and all is good. It was something like $0.85 for the DID, and around $0.009/minute for calls. I
 think they offer "unlimited" plans as well. They also have a basic Cisco IOS configuration for their service, so I think I may have a
 provider to use with my dial-up ISP project.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_voip.html'>voip</a>, <a href='tag_payphone.html'>payphone</a></p>









<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/voipms.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/voipms.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./voipms.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 14:09:04 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
The Arrow and the Song
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p><cite>The Arrow and the Song</cite><br />
&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;by Henry Wadsworth Longfellow</p>
<p>
I shot an arrow into the air,<br />
It fell to earth, I knew not where;<br />
For, so swiftly it flew, the sight<br />
Could not follow it in its flight.<br />
<br />
I breathed a song into the air,<br />
It fell to earth, I knew not where;<br />
For who has sight so keen and strong,<br />
That it can follow the flight of song?<br />
<br />
Long, long afterward, in an oak<br />
I found the arrow, still unbroke;<br />
And the song, from beginning to end,<br />
I found again in the heart of a friend.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_poetry.html'>poetry</a></p>









<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/the-arrow-and-the-song.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/the-arrow-and-the-song.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./the-arrow-and-the-song.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 07:56:54 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Home Automation
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p><img src="images/Homarr.jpg" width="100%" /></p>

<p>I've been playing around with TrueNAS, Home Assistant, and the like, and set up the above control panel
so that I can view the status of apps and various sensors in my home. There's so much more that can be
done, but this is a start. ;)</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_truenas.html'>truenas</a>, <a href='tag_networking.html'>networking</a>, <a href='tag_homarr.html'>homarr</a></p>









<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/home-automation.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/home-automation.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./home-automation.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 14:58:45 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Cloudflare
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I may, at some point, move this site back to self-hosting, as I have managed
to get a reverse-proxy setup so that <a href="http://lg15.cassieiswatching.com">lg15.cassieiswatching.com</a>  works whichever
upstream ISP is working at the moment. This allows me to self-host even if
carrier-grade NAT is being used. I suggest watching the embedded video for a
quick how-to.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/h5fAcE70xbQ?si=JshI4y9xJnkoWuBu" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_hosting.html'>hosting</a>, <a href='tag_nat.html'>nat</a>, <a href='tag_cloudflare.html'>cloudflare</a>, <a href='tag_cloudflared.html'>cloudflared</a></p>









<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/cloudflare.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/cloudflare.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./cloudflare.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 23:25:21 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Screaming into the void
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>For the two people following here, you may have noticed that I've been 
 screaming into the void a bit more often that I was. I have been turning here
 instead of Facebook a bit more whenever I have something to say. It seems to
 help me stay off of FB a bit more. ;)</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_blogging.html'>blogging</a></p>









<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/screaming-into-the-void.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/screaming-into-the-void.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./screaming-into-the-void.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 15:00:26 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Payphone
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Some time ago, I purchaced a refurbished payphone online. I bought it
 unprogrammed, as I wasn't sure how I wanted to set it up, but had some issues
 getting it to keep some of my settings. I had plugged the internal battery in,
 and had followed all the instructions. Yet my changes to change collection
 never seemed to last. Well, recently I also discovered that the phone wasn't
 working at all. I opened the phone and removed the battery and tested it, and
 it was dead. So I thought I'd take the board out and see if I could bypass it
 coin collection completely, and I discovered a second battery on the back of
 the board. So I did a little more digging, and discovered the first battery
 apparently provided power to the relay, and the one I discovered powers the
 chip which saves the setting. I tested it, and the voltage measured a bit low
 as well. Replacement batteries ordered, so I should finally be able to set the
 phone the way I'd like it set.</p>

<p>In the process, I also discovered a blog post about <a href="https://philtel.org/2022/06/27/fixing-a-protel-pt1.html">fixing a Protel payphone</a>.
 It appears to be more-or-less the same phone as I have, and has a lot of
 interesting information that I hadn't run across before. Worth checking out if
 you're interested in such things at all.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_protel.html'>protel</a>, <a href='tag_payphone.html'>payphone</a>, <a href='tag_retro.html'>retro</a></p>









<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/payphone.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/payphone.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./payphone.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 09:39:57 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Gotta Keep It Separated
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Most people who know me personally don't know this, but I have been separated
 from my wife on-and-off for the past few years. I posted to FB when it happened
 but that upset my wife, so I deleted the post. I was hoping to work things out,
 but that looks less and less likely. We're still best friends, and are probably
 better for each other separately than as a couple. We're co-parenting well, and
 all is fine, which is why I never told anyone else since that initial post. If 
 this is how you're finding out, I'm sorry for not telling you sooner. I just
 don't care to talk about it because I am fine and don't want it to be what
 people focus on when they're around me.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_family.html'>family</a></p>









<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/gotta-keep-it-separated.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/gotta-keep-it-separated.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./gotta-keep-it-separated.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 08:57:47 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
No further news of my father's passing
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>A few weeks ago, I posted about <a href="/on-the-passing-of-my-father.html">my father's passing on January 14</a>. Since then, I
 have heard absolutely nothing. I find it peculiar that I still cannot find his 
 obituary or notice of his funeral or anything else about it online. I expected 
 to at least see a post on Facebook by the half-sister who notified me, but I 
 have not even seen that. I find this rather... peculiar... </p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_family.html'>family</a></p>









<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/no-further-news-of-my-fathers-passing.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/no-further-news-of-my-fathers-passing.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./no-further-news-of-my-fathers-passing.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 16:54:15 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Feedburner
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I just realized that I failed to update my <a href="/feed.rss">rss feed</a> to use <a href="https://feeds.feedburner.com/wintermutesblog">Feedburner</a>, so have rectified that. The original one provided by the software still works, but I just realized that my blog's two followers probably stopped getting updates a long time ago. lol</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_blog.html'>blog</a>, <a href='tag_rss.html'>rss</a>, <a href='tag_feed.html'>feed</a>, <a href='tag_feedburner.html'>feedburner</a></p>









<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/feedburner.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/feedburner.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./feedburner.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 15:43:44 -0500</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
