<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Nitemare Cafe</title><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/index.html</link>
<description>A day in the life of a computer geek</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:07:04 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:07:04 -0500</pubDate>
<atom:link href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
One the passing of my father
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>On Tuesday, I got word from my half-sister that my father has passed away. I 
 believe he was 85 years old. This has led to some rather complex emotions over 
 the passed couple of days.</p>

<p>For a little background, my parents divorsed when I was young. I'm not sure 
 exactly how old I was because my childhood memories are extremely fuzzy, plus 
 my  perception of time seems scewed to begin with, but I would guess around 
 five years old. I say this because I have a vague recollection of starting 
 school in one school and my mom walking me to that school. Then I remember
 transferring to another school in kindergarden, and I remember the house we
 lived in when I went to the second one, and we lived there with my dad and
 step-mother (my dad's third wife, as I recall). So obviously my father got
 custody of my sisters (one younger, one older) and I.</p>

<p>When I was 8, we moved to Florida. After a year and a half or so, my older
 sister decided she wanted to go live with our mom and step-dad. Our father
 agreed to let her and my sister go live there, since he didn't want to
 separate the two. But at 9, he gave me the choice to stay with him or go with
 my sisters. For the longest time, I hated him for making me choose my sisters
 over him, but obviously did.</p>

<p>I only saw or spoke to him once after that, and it was when I was a teen and
 still bitter about it. I have long since let that hatred, anger, and bitterness
 go, and replaced them with... nothing...</p>

<p>For his part, I don't know much about what happened after my sisters and I
 left. I know he remarried his fourh wife, and he had three more children with
 her. Two more girls and a boy. That marraige lasted until her passing a year or two ago.</p>

<p>For my part, I realize that he was probably afraid that I'd have felt pushed
 away, so thought he was sparing me that by giving me a choice. I suspect he
 already knew the outcome, or didn't plan on separate us and would have talked
 me into going with me sisters.</p>

<p>Because I knew he was getting up there in age, and I'm in my 50s and becoming
 more and more aware of my own mortality, I'd recently started thinging about
 getting in touch, if just to let him know I didn't hold any annimosity. I've
 also thought about getting ahold of my half-siblings, whom I've never met, to
 see if they would help me know him through their eyes. I don't remember much
 about my father, and it is tainted by all those years of resentment.</p>

<p>His passing has triggered some very vague and fuzzy memories, though, and I 
 can only speculate on what I remember correctly, and what my mind is filling
 in.</p>

<p>For instance, I have a very fuzzy memory if it being nighttime, us being 
 outside at our grandparents' home, and flashing lights, someone holding a baby
 on the porch (either my mom or grandma holding my little sister, most likely),
 and my dad standing with his hands behind his back like a soldier standing at-
 ease. I seem to remember someone screaming at my father, probably my mother,
 and maybe police? The flashing lights were maybe from their cars? Maybe my dad
 was getting arrested for a domestic situation?</p>

<p>I also think maybe the divorce was a result of my mom cheating on him. It was
 the 70's, and courts usually favored the mother when it came to custody, of all
 my friends growing up who had divorced parents, very few of their fathers had
 even split custody. So the only way my father would have gotten custody is if
 my mother just okay, or if she had caused the end of the marraige.</p>

<p>This is just speculation, of course, but now there is no one who could verify
 any of it. My older sister passed away over nine years ago, and we never really
 talked about our father. My little sisted was just a baby, and had cut tied
 with the family regardless. I doubt my half-siblings would have heard much
 about his previous life.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_family.html'>family</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/one-the-passing-of-my-father.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/one-the-passing-of-my-father.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./one-the-passing-of-my-father.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:06:58 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Thermostat
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>A silent scream. A monster in the machine. The monster is me.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_puzzles.html'>puzzles</a>, <a href='tag_arg.html'>arg</a>, <a href='tag_scaremail.html'>scaremail</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/thermostat.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/thermostat.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./thermostat.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 14:46:49 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Discord
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>If you have JavaScript enabled, you should see my Discord server below. If not, you can join us <a href=" https://discord.com/channels/728352666106855526/728352666106855528">here</a>.</p>
<widgetbot
  server="728352666106855526"
  channel="728352666106855528"
  width="800"
  height="600"
></widgetbot>
<script src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/@widgetbot/html-embed"></script>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_discord.html'>discord</a>, <a href='tag_chat.html'>chat</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/discord.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/discord.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./discord.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:52:28 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
NAS
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>For quite some time, I have beeing building servers out of outdated computers to use as network-attached storage but throwing as much storage into it as I can afford at the time.  I've currently got a moderately powerful early-generation i7 with 3 8TB drives in it (plus a separate 2TB boot and applications drive) running everything, but it is not very power-efficient, being probably a decade old or more at this point. So, I finally ordered my first proper NAS because if there's a chance I'll be living out of the RV at some point, I would like something a bit more power-friendly since I only have 30-amp service there. I plan to upgrade that at some point, and also go solar, but limiting my power requirements probably isn't a bad idea in general.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_computers.html'>computers</a>, <a href='tag_networking.html'>networking</a>, <a href='tag_storage.html'>storage</a>, <a href='tag_nas.html'>nas</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/nas.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/nas.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./nas.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 12:27:04 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Scaremail
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>
<center><a href="https://davidviergutz.com/rod65"><img src="images/scaremail.jpg" alt="scaremail" /></a></center></p>
<p>It's not quite an ARG, but it has many elements of one. Horror author David Viergutz has created a very ARG-like experience delivered as two letters per month for a year, which I bought for my wife some time back. I decided I wanted my own copy, so I ordered it for myself as well about a month later, putting me two letters behind her in the experience. There are websites to visit, phone numbers to call, etc., though I don't believe they will have much impact on the story other than making it feel more interactive. I'm currently eight letters in, out of twenty-four, and it is starting to get a bit creepy. The story is told as letters back and forth between a reader and David, with several other artifacts being included along the way. I've been enjoying it so much that I've been thinking CiW could use the same type of treatment, and if I could get more than an introductory letter, I'd probably launch something similar. ;)
</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_arg.html'>arg</a>, <a href='tag_scaremail.html'>scaremail</a>, <a href='tag_scare.me.html'>scare.me</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/scaremail.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/scaremail.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./scaremail.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 17:48:37 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
lg15.com
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>The official <a href="http://www.lg15.com">lg15.com</a> has been down for a few weeks now, and I have contacted Miles about it. While he responded when I first noticed it by saying he would check into it and asking if I wanted to help maintain it, he has not responded to any further inquiries. I do not know where it stands, but it appears that the web server has been shut down for some reason. It should be a matter of the hosting company starting it back up, and then the official site is back.</a>

<p>That said, I am not one to wait around. ;) Since I have a bunch of the databases from when I previously helped to restore lgpedia, I set up an unofficial mirror at <a href="http://lg15.cassieiswatching.com">lg15.cassieiswatching.com</a>. I couldn't get the old version of phpBB2 to work properly, so I upgraded the forums to phpBB3. There's a quirk with the "last post" author and date, but otherwise all the old posts from 2007-ish are still there. For lgpedia, I just linked to an existing fan mirror of it.</p>

<p>I built this on top of a couple old projects I had written for Cassie Watchers. The first one was a <a href="http://lg15.cassieiswatching.com/index.php">search</a> for the forums. The second was another search, this time for the <a href="http://lg15.cassieiswatching.com/comments.php">comments</a> from the old Wordpress version of the site. And finally, I had put together a list of all the <a href="http://lg15.cassieiswatching.com/Videos.php">videos</a> as a list of the old posts along with their comments.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_lonelygirl15.html'>lonelygirl15</a>, <a href='tag_lg15.html'>lg15</a>, <a href='tag_cassieiswatching.html'>cassieiswatching</a>, <a href='tag_ciw.html'>ciw</a></p>




<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/lg15com.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/lg15com.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./lg15com.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 11:34:20 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
New Project: Dialup ISP
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I have an old USR Total Control from Greenapple, and have been pondering how to put it back into service for awhile now. Looks like these guys have figured it out:<p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GQ0KTtMQ_8s?si=mVq7ksb_QOJaL7zZ" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe><p>
<p>I hope to be able to duplicate their work. Why? Is it practical? No, it's not practical. But because I can? lol</p>
<p>Tags: <a href='tag_dialup.html'>dialup</a>, <a href='tag_isp.html'>isp</a>, <a href='tag_usr-total-control.html'>usr-total-control</a></p>




<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/new-project-dialup-isp.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/new-project-dialup-isp.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./new-project-dialup-isp.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 08:04:38 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Cross Country 2024
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I intended to do updates of my daughter's Cross Country <a href="https://www.nitemarecafe.com/running.html">running</a> times, but time got away from me. Instead, here's summary of her 2024 season:</p>
<p>Her first 1 mile race that I posed about was on 8/24, and she finished in 10:27.</p>
<p>During her following practice on 8/26, she ran a 14:36 mile. The slower time is probably due to the hotter weather, the practice course being a bit rougher, and she had just competed in her first race and didn't have any recocery time.<p>
<p>She ran a 12:31 mile on 8/31.</p>
<p>On 9/6, she had her first 2K race and finished in 13:54.</p>
<p>On 9/17, she broke a 10 minute mile with a time of 9:52.</p>
<p>Three days later, she ran another 2K and finished in 13:08.</p>
<p>Her last race of the season was her longest yet, a 3K which she finished in 20:06.</p>
<p>To cap off her season, there was one last timed mile at practice the following Monday, which she finished in 9:19, which was over five minutes faster than her first practice timed run and a over a minute faster than her first race.</p>
<p>I am so proud of this girl's accomplishments this season, setting a new personal best almost every time she ran during her very first season of cross country.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_running.html'>running</a>, <a href='tag_cross-country.html'>cross-country</a></p>





<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/cross-country-2024.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/cross-country-2024.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./cross-country-2024.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:17:06 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Comments Enabled
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I don't like running a blog where I cannot interact with users, so comments are now enabled via <a href="https://disqus.com/">Disqus</a>. Unfortunately, it embeds 3rd-party JavaScript into the site in order to do so, but the only other way would be to do some forms, receiving those forms via email, and processing them via some hacked-together script. Since I prefer to moderate comments to keep spam away anyhow, this might not be so bad a solution, but Disqus is a little easier to do without much effort ;)
</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_blogging.html'>blogging</a>, <a href='tag_comments.html'>comments</a></p>










<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/comments-enabled.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/comments-enabled.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./comments-enabled.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 16:14:29 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Running
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p><center>
	<img src="images/53946676093_5f8a048125_o.jpg" alt="Mikaylee's First Race" />
</center></p>
<p>My 10yo daughter is in Cross Country this year, and this is her finishing her first-ever race with a 10:27.42 mile. This is about 2 minutes faster than an average 10yo beginner, and just a few seconds faster than an average 10yo novice. This papa is so proud of his little girl.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_running.html'>running</a>, <a href='tag_family.html'>family</a></p>











<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/running.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/running.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./running.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:10:56 -0400</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
