<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Nitemare Cafe</title><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/index.html</link>
<description>A day in the life of a computer geek</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 16:54:17 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 16:54:17 -0500</pubDate>
<atom:link href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
No further news of my father's passing
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>A few weeks ago, I posted about <a href="https://www.nitemarecafe.com/on-the-passing-of-my-father.html">my father's passing on January 14</a>. Since then, I
 have heard absolutely nothing. I find it peculiar that I still cannot find his 
 obituary or notice of his funeral or anything else about it online. I expected 
 to at least see a post on Facebook by the half-sister who notified me, but I 
 have not even seen that. I find this rather... peculiar... </p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_family.html'>family</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/no-further-news-of-my-fathers-passing.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/no-further-news-of-my-fathers-passing.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./no-further-news-of-my-fathers-passing.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 16:54:15 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Feedburner
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I just realized that I failed to update my <a href="https://www.nitemarecafe.com/feed.rss">rss feed</a> to use <a href="https://feeds.feedburner.com/wintermutesblog">Feedburner</a>, so have rectified that. The original one provided by the software still works, but I just realized that my blog's two followers probably stopped getting updates a long time ago. lol</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_blog.html'>blog</a>, <a href='tag_rss.html'>rss</a>, <a href='tag_feed.html'>feed</a>, <a href='tag_feedburner.html'>feedburner</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/feedburner.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/feedburner.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./feedburner.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 15:43:44 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
One-word review: Dog Man
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Dud</p>

<p>Slightly longer review: I know. It's a movie meant for kids. My 10yo daughter 
loves the books. She and my 6yo daughter seemed to enjoy it, but I was sitting 
there feeling like I was in a 5-hour documentary on paperclips. Many kid's movies
have plenty of humor aimed at the adults in the audience, but if this movie had 
any of that I completely missed it. I think I laughed once as something that was 
slightly humorous. The "Bad Guys" short they showed before the movie was 
hilarious, though. ;)</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_one-word-reviews.html'>one-word-reviews</a>, <a href='tag_movies.html'>movies</a>, <a href='tag_reviews.html'>reviews</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/one-word-review-dog-man.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/one-word-review-dog-man.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./one-word-review-dog-man.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 08:55:56 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Network redesign
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I'm starting to redesign my home newtwork. I started by getting a new router which allows
muliple WANs, with automatic failover from one to the other, because my primary ISP frequently
has short outages during my workday. Since them, I've also upgraded my server from an old
gaming PC to an actual NAS, running the same services I was on the server but via docker
containers. I still have a couple services to move over, but that is mostly done. I also
plan to upgrade my WiFi and such. I went with TPlink, as they are low-cost but offer the same
functionality as many of the enterprise solutions out there. The router is already TP-Link,
and I just purchased the controller. Next payday, I'll probably pick up a couple of APs and
probably a POE switch.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_tplink.html'>tplink</a>, <a href='tag_networking.html'>networking</a>, <a href='tag_wifi.html'>wifi</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/network-redesign.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/network-redesign.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./network-redesign.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 12:52:55 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Severance
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I posted this on FB, but I plan on giving that up soon, so I am repeating it here:</p>

<p>Someone in a CRT group (on FB), of all places, recently recommended the TV show <i>Severance</i>, a few weeks before season 2 started. So I binged it to be ready for season 2, and it is a wonderfully quirky show which you'll either love or hate. People go through a procedure to separate their work lives from the rest of their lives. Literally. While they're an "innie," they have no memory of the outside world. They have no knowledge of their "outie's" lives at all. To them, they're always at the office. And the opposite is true. Their "outie" has no knowledge of their "innie's" lives, and none of their memories. They go to work, and their next memory is of them leaving work. It's an interesting concept on it's own, but there's also a strange cult, and rituals. Definitely worth checking out.</p>

<p>On a related note, Apple TV+ is also adapting <i>Neuromancer</i> to TV, and has completed a couple of weeks of shooting in Tokyo so far. I'm <b>really</b> looking forward to that one!</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_tv.html'>tv</a>, <a href='tag_severance.html'>severance</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/severance.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/severance.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./severance.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 10:04:31 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Navbar
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I decided to add a navbar, because it may help someone find something they're looking for at some point, and rather than expend the braincells to do the minimal work to create the CSS from scratch, I just Googled it. And the colors used were perfect as-is. lol</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_navbar.html'>navbar</a>, <a href='tag_site.html'>site</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/navbar.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/navbar.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./navbar.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 21:26:39 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
On the passing of my father
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>On Tuesday, I got word from my half-sister that my father has passed away. I 
 believe he was 85 years old. This has led to some rather complex emotions over 
 the passed couple of days.</p>

<p>For a little background, my parents divorsed when I was young. I'm not sure 
 exactly how old I was because my childhood memories are extremely fuzzy, plus 
 my  perception of time seems scewed to begin with, but I would guess around 
 five years old. I say this because I have a vague recollection of starting 
 school in one school and my mom walking me to that school. Then I remember
 transferring to another school in kindergarden, and I remember the house we
 lived in when I went to the second one, and we lived there with my dad and
 step-mother (my dad's third wife, as I recall). So obviously my father got
 custody of my sisters (one younger, one older) and I.</p>

<p>When I was 8, we moved to Florida. After a year and a half or so, my older
 sister decided she wanted to go live with our mom and step-dad. Our father
 agreed to let her and my sister go live there, since he didn't want to
 separate the two. But at 9, he gave me the choice to stay with him or go with
 my sisters. For the longest time, I hated him for making me choose my sisters
 over him, but obviously did.</p>

<p>I only saw or spoke to him once after that, and it was when I was a teen and
 still bitter about it. I have long since let that hatred, anger, and bitterness
 go, and replaced them with... nothing...</p>

<p>For his part, I don't know much about what happened after my sisters and I
 left. I know he remarried his fourh wife, and he had three more children with
 her. Two more girls and a boy. That marraige lasted until her passing a year or two ago.</p>

<p>For my part, I realize that he was probably afraid that I'd have felt pushed
 away, so thought he was sparing me that by giving me a choice. I suspect he
 already knew the outcome, or didn't plan on separate us and would have talked
 me into going with me sisters.</p>

<p>Because I knew he was getting up there in age, and I'm in my 50s and becoming
 more and more aware of my own mortality, I'd recently started thinging about
 getting in touch, if just to let him know I didn't hold any annimosity. I've
 also thought about getting ahold of my half-siblings, whom I've never met, to
 see if they would help me know him through their eyes. I don't remember much
 about my father, and it is tainted by all those years of resentment.</p>

<p>His passing has triggered some very vague and fuzzy memories, though, and I 
 can only speculate on what I remember correctly, and what my mind is filling
 in.</p>

<p>For instance, I have a very fuzzy memory if it being nighttime, us being 
 outside at our grandparents' home, and flashing lights, someone holding a baby
 on the porch (either my mom or grandma holding my little sister, most likely),
 and my dad standing with his hands behind his back like a soldier standing at-
 ease. I seem to remember someone screaming at my father, probably my mother,
 and maybe police? The flashing lights were maybe from their cars? Maybe my dad
 was getting arrested for a domestic situation?</p>

<p>I also think maybe the divorce was a result of my mom cheating on him. It was
 the 70's, and courts usually favored the mother when it came to custody, of all
 my friends growing up who had divorced parents, very few of their fathers had
 even split custody. So the only way my father would have gotten custody is if
 my mother just okay, or if she had caused the end of the marraige.</p>

<p>This is just speculation, of course, but now there is no one who could verify
 any of it. My older sister passed away over nine years ago, and we never really
 talked about our father. My little sisted was just a baby, and had cut tied
 with the family regardless. I doubt my half-siblings would have heard much
 about his previous life.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_family.html'>family</a></p>









<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/on-the-passing-of-my-father.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/on-the-passing-of-my-father.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./on-the-passing-of-my-father.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 10:06:58 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Thermostat
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>A silent scream. A monster in the machine. The monster is me.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_puzzles.html'>puzzles</a>, <a href='tag_arg.html'>arg</a>, <a href='tag_scaremail.html'>scaremail</a></p>









<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/thermostat.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/thermostat.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./thermostat.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 14:46:49 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Discord
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>If you have JavaScript enabled, you should see my Discord server below. If not, you can join us <a href=" https://discord.com/channels/728352666106855526/728352666106855528">here</a>.</p>
<widgetbot
  server="728352666106855526"
  channel="728352666106855528"
  width="800"
  height="600"
></widgetbot>
<script src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/@widgetbot/html-embed"></script>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_discord.html'>discord</a>, <a href='tag_chat.html'>chat</a></p>








<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/discord.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/discord.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./discord.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:52:28 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
NAS
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>For quite some time, I have beeing building servers out of outdated computers to use as network-attached storage but throwing as much storage into it as I can afford at the time.  I've currently got a moderately powerful early-generation i7 with 3 8TB drives in it (plus a separate 2TB boot and applications drive) running everything, but it is not very power-efficient, being probably a decade old or more at this point. So, I finally ordered my first proper NAS because if there's a chance I'll be living out of the RV at some point, I would like something a bit more power-friendly since I only have 30-amp service there. I plan to upgrade that at some point, and also go solar, but limiting my power requirements probably isn't a bad idea in general.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_computers.html'>computers</a>, <a href='tag_networking.html'>networking</a>, <a href='tag_storage.html'>storage</a>, <a href='tag_nas.html'>nas</a></p>









<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/nas.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/nas.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./nas.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 12:27:04 -0500</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
