<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Nitemare Cafe</title><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/index.html</link>
<description>A day in the life of a computer geek</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 21:59:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 21:59:44 -0500</pubDate>
<atom:link href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
Thermostat
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>A silent scream. A monster in the machine. The monster is me.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_puzzles.html'>puzzles</a>, <a href='tag_arg.html'>arg</a>, <a href='tag_scaremail.html'>scaremail</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/thermostat.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/thermostat.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./thermostat.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 14:46:49 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Discord
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>If you have JavaScript enabled, you should see my Discord server below. If not, you can join us <a href=" https://discord.com/channels/728352666106855526/728352666106855528">here</a>.</p>
<widgetbot
  server="728352666106855526"
  channel="728352666106855528"
  width="800"
  height="600"
></widgetbot>
<script src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/@widgetbot/html-embed"></script>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_discord.html'>discord</a>, <a href='tag_chat.html'>chat</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/discord.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/discord.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./discord.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 15:52:28 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
NAS
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>For quite some time, I have beeing building servers out of outdated computers to use as network-attached storage but throwing as much storage into it as I can afford at the time.  I've currently got a moderately powerful early-generation i7 with 3 8TB drives in it (plus a separate 2TB boot and applications drive) running everything, but it is not very power-efficient, being probably a decade old or more at this point. So, I finally ordered my first proper NAS because if there's a chance I'll be living out of the RV at some point, I would like something a bit more power-friendly since I only have 30-amp service there. I plan to upgrade that at some point, and also go solar, but limiting my power requirements probably isn't a bad idea in general.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_computers.html'>computers</a>, <a href='tag_networking.html'>networking</a>, <a href='tag_storage.html'>storage</a>, <a href='tag_nas.html'>nas</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/nas.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/nas.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./nas.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 12:27:04 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Scaremail
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>
<center><a href="https://davidviergutz.com/rod65"><img src="images/scaremail.jpg" alt="scaremail" /></a></center></p>
<p>It's not quite an ARG, but it has many elements of one. Horror author David Viergutz has created a very ARG-like experience delivered as two letters per month for a year, which I bought for my wife some time back. I decided I wanted my own copy, so I ordered it for myself as well about a month later, putting me two letters behind her in the experience. There are websites to visit, phone numbers to call, etc., though I don't believe they will have much impact on the story other than making it feel more interactive. I'm currently eight letters in, out of twenty-four, and it is starting to get a bit creepy. The story is told as letters back and forth between a reader and David, with several other artifacts being included along the way. I've been enjoying it so much that I've been thinking CiW could use the same type of treatment, and if I could get more than an introductory letter, I'd probably launch something similar. ;)
</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_arg.html'>arg</a>, <a href='tag_scaremail.html'>scaremail</a>, <a href='tag_scare.me.html'>scare.me</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/scaremail.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/scaremail.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./scaremail.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 17:48:37 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
lg15.com
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>The official <a href="http://www.lg15.com">lg15.com</a> has been down for a few weeks now, and I have contacted Miles about it. While he responded when I first noticed it by saying he would check into it and asking if I wanted to help maintain it, he has not responded to any further inquiries. I do not know where it stands, but it appears that the web server has been shut down for some reason. It should be a matter of the hosting company starting it back up, and then the official site is back.</a>

<p>That said, I am not one to wait around. ;) Since I have a bunch of the databases from when I previously helped to restore lgpedia, I set up an unofficial mirror at <a href="http://lg15.cassieiswatching.com">lg15.cassieiswatching.com</a>. I couldn't get the old version of phpBB2 to work properly, so I upgraded the forums to phpBB3. There's a quirk with the "last post" author and date, but otherwise all the old posts from 2007-ish are still there. For lgpedia, I just linked to an existing fan mirror of it.</p>

<p>I built this on top of a couple old projects I had written for Cassie Watchers. The first one was a <a href="http://lg15.cassieiswatching.com/index.php">search</a> for the forums. The second was another search, this time for the <a href="http://lg15.cassieiswatching.com/comments.php">comments</a> from the old Wordpress version of the site. And finally, I had put together a list of all the <a href="http://lg15.cassieiswatching.com/Videos.php">videos</a> as a list of the old posts along with their comments.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_lonelygirl15.html'>lonelygirl15</a>, <a href='tag_lg15.html'>lg15</a>, <a href='tag_cassieiswatching.html'>cassieiswatching</a>, <a href='tag_ciw.html'>ciw</a></p>




<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/lg15com.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/lg15com.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./lg15com.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 11:34:20 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
New Project: Dialup ISP
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I have an old USR Total Control from Greenapple, and have been pondering how to put it back into service for awhile now. Looks like these guys have figured it out:<p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GQ0KTtMQ_8s?si=mVq7ksb_QOJaL7zZ" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe><p>
<p>I hope to be able to duplicate their work. Why? Is it practical? No, it's not practical. But because I can? lol</p>
<p>Tags: <a href='tag_dialup.html'>dialup</a>, <a href='tag_isp.html'>isp</a>, <a href='tag_usr-total-control.html'>usr-total-control</a></p>




<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/new-project-dialup-isp.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/new-project-dialup-isp.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./new-project-dialup-isp.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 08:04:38 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Cross Country 2024
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I intended to do updates of my daughter's Cross Country <a href="https://www.nitemarecafe.com/running.html">running</a> times, but time got away from me. Instead, here's summary of her 2024 season:</p>
<p>Her first 1 mile race that I posed about was on 8/24, and she finished in 10:27.</p>
<p>During her following practice on 8/26, she ran a 14:36 mile. The slower time is probably due to the hotter weather, the practice course being a bit rougher, and she had just competed in her first race and didn't have any recocery time.<p>
<p>She ran a 12:31 mile on 8/31.</p>
<p>On 9/6, she had her first 2K race and finished in 13:54.</p>
<p>On 9/17, she broke a 10 minute mile with a time of 9:52.</p>
<p>Three days later, she ran another 2K and finished in 13:08.</p>
<p>Her last race of the season was her longest yet, a 3K which she finished in 20:06.</p>
<p>To cap off her season, there was one last timed mile at practice the following Monday, which she finished in 9:19, which was over five minutes faster than her first practice timed run and a over a minute faster than her first race.</p>
<p>I am so proud of this girl's accomplishments this season, setting a new personal best almost every time she ran during her very first season of cross country.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_running.html'>running</a>, <a href='tag_cross-country.html'>cross-country</a></p>





<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/cross-country-2024.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/cross-country-2024.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./cross-country-2024.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 11:17:06 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Comments Enabled
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I don't like running a blog where I cannot interact with users, so comments are now enabled via <a href="https://disqus.com/">Disqus</a>. Unfortunately, it embeds 3rd-party JavaScript into the site in order to do so, but the only other way would be to do some forms, receiving those forms via email, and processing them via some hacked-together script. Since I prefer to moderate comments to keep spam away anyhow, this might not be so bad a solution, but Disqus is a little easier to do without much effort ;)
</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_blogging.html'>blogging</a>, <a href='tag_comments.html'>comments</a></p>










<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/comments-enabled.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/comments-enabled.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./comments-enabled.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 16:14:29 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Running
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p><center>
	<img src="images/53946676093_5f8a048125_o.jpg" alt="Mikaylee's First Race" />
</center></p>
<p>My 10yo daughter is in Cross Country this year, and this is her finishing her first-ever race with a 10:27.42 mile. This is about 2 minutes faster than an average 10yo beginner, and just a few seconds faster than an average 10yo novice. This papa is so proud of his little girl.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_running.html'>running</a>, <a href='tag_family.html'>family</a></p>











<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/running.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/running.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./running.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 09:10:56 -0400</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
One by one, the penguins are stealing my sanity (yet again)
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>At this point, I can't even remember where the title of this post comes from. All I know is that ever since I read that somewhere else, every iteration of this blog has had a post with that title. I had to keep the tradition alive. ;)</p>
<p>I am a fan of paranormal shows. UFOs, ghost hunting, etc. I've had some experience which, when I was younger, attributed to the paranormal. I still cannot explain those experiences, but I no longer attribute them to something paranormal. It's easy to miss some detail that would explain things perfectly and have your imagination fill in the rest, especially if it were primed to do so.</p>
<p>But this post isn't about my experiences. This is about a rabbit hole that I just got sucked into by my 10yo daughter. We had taken my girls to King's Island a week or so ago, and my wife had pointed out a restaurant which she thought was the one featured on <i>Ghost Hunters</i> because my 10yo loves watching reruns of the show. This morning, my 10yo wanted to watch that episode, which is S8E01, "Roller Ghoster." My daughter mentioned that she didn't think it was the same restaurant that my wife had mentioned, but thought maybe it had changed names. She was correct on the first count. My wife had pointed out the wrong restaurant.</p>

<p>During my research I discovered a <a href="https://browsingtheatlas.com/2012/10/05/the-ghosts-of-kings-island/">brief post</a> by an area local who remembered a story about a teen who fell to death climbing the Eifel Tower on May 13, 1983. Naturally, since the claim is that it happened on Friday the 13th, the first stop was to verify that the date was, indeed, a Friday. I was somewhat surprised that it was. "Okay," I thought. So, someone made something up because it was a Friday the 13th. But the post did include a name, and searching for "John Harter 1983 obituary" confirms the rest of the story (aside from the underage drinking, but being 1983 and a graduation celbration, that detail isn't much of a stretch). Though it's hard to say if there's more to the article behind a paywall, or of the blurb is all it got, it did make the <h ref=https://www.nytimes.com/1983/05/15/us/death-at-graduation-party.html">NY Times</a>. I would love to know what ghost stories surround this incident.</p>

<p>This also reminds me of a project I've been meaning to do for the <a href="https://www.nitemarecafe.com/tag_ghosts-of-ohio.html">Ghosts of Ohio</a> section of the site. I need to catalog, review, and further research the <i>Ghost Hunters</i> episodes which take place in my home state. If anyone wants to contribute stories related to any of the <i>Ghost Hunters</i> episode locations, or <a href="https://www.nitemarecafe.com/tag_ghosts-of-ohio.html">Ghosts of Ohio</a> in general, email me at wintermute AT nitematecafe DOT com.</p>


<p>Tags: <a href='tag_ghost-hunters.html'>ghost-hunters</a>, <a href='tag_taps.html'>taps</a>, <a href='tag_ghosts-of-ohio.html'>ghosts-of-ohio</a>, <a href='tag_paranormal.html'>paranormal</a></p>











<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/one-by-one-the-penguins-are-stealing-my-sanity-yet-again.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/one-by-one-the-penguins-are-stealing-my-sanity-yet-again.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./one-by-one-the-penguins-are-stealing-my-sanity-yet-again.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 13:41:08 -0400</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
