<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Nitemare Cafe</title><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/index.html</link>
<description>A day in the life of a computer geek</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 14:58:47 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 14:58:47 -0500</pubDate>
<atom:link href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
Home Automation
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p><img src="images/Homarr.jpg" /></p>

<p>I've been playing around with TrueNAS, Home Assistant, and the like, and set up the above control panel
so that I can view the status of apps and various sensors in my home. There's so much more that can be
done, but this is a start. ;)</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_truenas.html'>truenas</a>, <a href='tag_networking.html'>networking</a>, <a href='tag_homarr.html'>homarr</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/home-automation.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/home-automation.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./home-automation.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 14:58:45 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Cloudflare
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I may, at some point, move this site back to self-hosting, as I have managed
to get a reverse-proxy setup so that <a href="lg15.cassieiswatching.com">lg15.cassieiswatching.com</a>  works whichever
upstream ISP is working at the moment. This allows me to self-host even if
carrier-grade NAT is being used. I suggest watching the embedded video for a
quick how-to.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/h5fAcE70xbQ?si=JshI4y9xJnkoWuBu" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_hosting.html'>hosting</a>, <a href='tag_nat.html'>nat</a>, <a href='tag_cloudflare.html'>cloudflare</a>, <a href='tag_cloudflared.html'>cloudflared</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/cloudflare.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/cloudflare.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./cloudflare.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 23:25:21 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Screaming into the void
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>For the two people following here, you may have noticed that I've been 
 screaming into the void a bit more often that I was. I have been turning here
 instead of Facebook a bit more whenever I have something to say. It seems to
 help me stay off of FB a bit more. ;)</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_blogging.html'>blogging</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/screaming-into-the-void.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/screaming-into-the-void.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./screaming-into-the-void.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 15:00:26 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Payphone
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Some time ago, I purchaced a refurbished payphone online. I bought it
 unprogrammed, as I wasn't sure how I wanted to set it up, but had some issues
 getting it to keep some of my settings. I had plugged the internal battery in,
 and had followed all the instructions. Yet my changes to change collection
 never seemed to last. Well, recently I also discovered that the phone wasn't
 working at all. I opened the phone and removed the battery and tested it, and
 it was dead. So I thought I'd take the board out and see if I could bypass it
 coin collection completely, and I discovered a second battery on the back of
 the board. So I did a little more digging, and discovered the first battery
 apparently provided power to the relay, and the one I discovered powers the
 chip which saves the setting. I tested it, and the voltage measured a bit low
 as well. Replacement batteries ordered, so I should finally be able to set the
 phone the way I'd like it set.</p>

<p>In the process, I also discovered a blog post about <a href="https://philtel.org/2022/06/27/fixing-a-protel-pt1.html">fixing a Protel payphone</a>.
 It appears to be more-or-less the same phone as I have, and has a lot of
 interesting information that I hadn't run across before. Worth checking out if
 you're interested in such things at all.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_protel.html'>protel</a>, <a href='tag_payphone.html'>payphone</a>, <a href='tag_retro.html'>retro</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/payphone.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/payphone.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./payphone.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 09:39:57 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Gotta Keep It Separated
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Most people who know me personally don't know this, but I have been separated
 from my wife on-and-off for the past few years. I posted to FB when it happened
 but that upset my wife, so I deleted the post. I was hoping to work things out,
 but that looks less and less likely. We're still best friends, and are probably
 better for each other separately than as a couple. We're co-parenting well, and
 all is fine, which is why I never told anyone else since that initial post. If 
 this is how you're finding out, I'm sorry for not telling you sooner. I just
 don't care to talk about it because I am fine and don't want it to be what
 people focus on when they're around me.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_family.html'>family</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/gotta-keep-it-separated.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/gotta-keep-it-separated.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./gotta-keep-it-separated.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 08:57:47 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
No further news of my father's passing
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>A few weeks ago, I posted about <a href="https://www.nitemarecafe.com/on-the-passing-of-my-father.html">my father's passing on January 14</a>. Since then, I
 have heard absolutely nothing. I find it peculiar that I still cannot find his 
 obituary or notice of his funeral or anything else about it online. I expected 
 to at least see a post on Facebook by the half-sister who notified me, but I 
 have not even seen that. I find this rather... peculiar... </p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_family.html'>family</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/no-further-news-of-my-fathers-passing.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/no-further-news-of-my-fathers-passing.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./no-further-news-of-my-fathers-passing.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 16:54:15 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Feedburner
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I just realized that I failed to update my <a href="https://www.nitemarecafe.com/feed.rss">rss feed</a> to use <a href="https://feeds.feedburner.com/wintermutesblog">Feedburner</a>, so have rectified that. The original one provided by the software still works, but I just realized that my blog's two followers probably stopped getting updates a long time ago. lol</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_blog.html'>blog</a>, <a href='tag_rss.html'>rss</a>, <a href='tag_feed.html'>feed</a>, <a href='tag_feedburner.html'>feedburner</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/feedburner.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/feedburner.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./feedburner.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 15:43:44 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
One-word review: Dog Man
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Dud</p>

<p>Slightly longer review: I know. It's a movie meant for kids. My 10yo daughter 
loves the books. She and my 6yo daughter seemed to enjoy it, but I was sitting 
there feeling like I was in a 5-hour documentary on paperclips. Many kid's movies
have plenty of humor aimed at the adults in the audience, but if this movie had 
any of that I completely missed it. I think I laughed once as something that was 
slightly humorous. The "Bad Guys" short they showed before the movie was 
hilarious, though. ;)</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_one-word-reviews.html'>one-word-reviews</a>, <a href='tag_movies.html'>movies</a>, <a href='tag_reviews.html'>reviews</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/one-word-review-dog-man.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/one-word-review-dog-man.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./one-word-review-dog-man.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 08:55:56 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Network redesign
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I'm starting to redesign my home newtwork. I started by getting a new router which allows
muliple WANs, with automatic failover from one to the other, because my primary ISP frequently
has short outages during my workday. Since them, I've also upgraded my server from an old
gaming PC to an actual NAS, running the same services I was on the server but via docker
containers. I still have a couple services to move over, but that is mostly done. I also
plan to upgrade my WiFi and such. I went with TPlink, as they are low-cost but offer the same
functionality as many of the enterprise solutions out there. The router is already TP-Link,
and I just purchased the controller. Next payday, I'll probably pick up a couple of APs and
probably a POE switch.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_tplink.html'>tplink</a>, <a href='tag_networking.html'>networking</a>, <a href='tag_wifi.html'>wifi</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/network-redesign.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/network-redesign.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./network-redesign.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 12:52:55 -0500</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Severance
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I posted this on FB, but I plan on giving that up soon, so I am repeating it here:</p>

<p>Someone in a CRT group (on FB), of all places, recently recommended the TV show <i>Severance</i>, a few weeks before season 2 started. So I binged it to be ready for season 2, and it is a wonderfully quirky show which you'll either love or hate. People go through a procedure to separate their work lives from the rest of their lives. Literally. While they're an "innie," they have no memory of the outside world. They have no knowledge of their "outie's" lives at all. To them, they're always at the office. And the opposite is true. Their "outie" has no knowledge of their "innie's" lives, and none of their memories. They go to work, and their next memory is of them leaving work. It's an interesting concept on it's own, but there's also a strange cult, and rituals. Definitely worth checking out.</p>

<p>On a related note, Apple TV+ is also adapting <i>Neuromancer</i> to TV, and has completed a couple of weeks of shooting in Tokyo so far. I'm <b>really</b> looking forward to that one!</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_tv.html'>tv</a>, <a href='tag_severance.html'>severance</a></p>

<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/severance.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/severance.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./severance.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 10:04:31 -0500</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
