<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel><title>Nitemare Cafe</title><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/</link>
<description>A day in the life of a computer geek</description><language>en</language>
<lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 10:21:32 -0400</lastBuildDate>
<pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 10:21:32 -0400</pubDate>
<atom:link href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<item><title>
Compaq LTE Elite 4/75CX
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p><img src="images/compaq_elite" width="100%" />"</p>

<p>This is the first repair from the group of machines I received from a friend.
 It is a Compaq 486DX4/75 laptop with a 9.5" screen, 16MB of RAM, and a 340MB hard
 drive. The hard drive a standard 2.5" IDE drive, but it's stuck inside and aluminum
 "can" with a proprietary connector exposed instead of the normal one. When I first
 performed a triage on the machine, it powered up, but the screen was shattered and
 the hard drive was dead, and the floppy drive was in need of repair.</p>

<p>I did some searching on eBay and found a 4/50CX for cheap. This unit was listed as
 non-working and appeared to have been dropped. The main thing I was looking at in
 the listings was the screens. Most either appears to have cracks or to be delaminating,
 or didn't show individual pictures. Because this one was is such rough shape, the
 seller took lots of photos showing all the damage; cracked plastic, broken hinges,
 missing trackball, etc. But the screen looked like it was in great shape. So I pulled
 the trigger.</p>

<p>When I received it, I didn't even test it. There's a good chance it would have fired
 right up and just needed extensive plastic repair to get it back into a reasonable
 condition. But it was a random busted laptop from eBay, not something my friend's
 father passed on to be restored and cared for. My friend new that I would take care
 of his old collection, which is how I wound up with a rather large collection of
 mostly laptops in need of some TLC. So I figured out how to open the screen and
 completely stripped everything from inside it, including the hinges. I disassembled
 this laptop's screen and swapped them. There was only two connectors which disconnected
 the screen and four screws holding it in, so it was a pretty easy task. Plastic this
 old is pretty brittle, though, so care was taken not to weaking the plastic where the
 hinges attach any more than it already was. I plugged the laptop in and powered it on,
 and was greeted with it counting up the RAM and a perfectly good screen!</p>

<p>Next up was the hard drive. I hadn't opened the "can" on the old one yet, so as far
 as I knew, it was a completely proprietary drive. I noticed that the part number on
 the donor machine's drive matched the part number on this one, so I figured I'd give it
 a try. Imagine my surprise when it fired right up and loaded Win95. I believe DOS/Win31
 would have been what this laptop shipped with, but I'll take the win. I know I'll have
 to prepare the can from the dead drive with a different solution at some point, but I'm
 happy with this drive for now.</p>

<p>At this point, I hadn't opened the laptop up except for the screen, but I wanted to
 see if the donor's floppy drive still worked, so I swapped those. In the process, I
 discovered some broken plastic parts inside so pulled them from the donor. Unfortunately,
 the floppy drive is dead. Research seems to indicate that it is a belt-driven drive, and
 the belts tend to melt over time. This is a problem for another day, though. As is a
 good cleaning. Aside from those, this machine is done, and I am completely happy that
 I was able to make good on the promise to keep it out of a landfill and get it running
 again.</p>

<p>Now I have a (potentially) working Elite 4/50CX with a busted screen and dead
 drives, as well was broken plastics, which I am unsure what I want to do with. I'm
 thinking of 3D-printing a case for the motherboard and such and using it with an external
 monitor. Then repairing the plastics and stuffing a Raspberry Pi into the shell. Or just
 testing and organizing all the leftover parts so that I have spares to help keep this
 one running. The CPU is socketed, so even the mainboard is the same between the two
 machines. Only the CPU speed is different.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_vintage.html'>vintage</a>, <a href='tag_computers.html'>computers</a>, <a href='tag_486.html'>486</a>, <a href='tag_compaq.html'>compaq</a>, <a href='tag_retro.html'>retro</a>, <a href='tag_win95.html'>win95</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/compaq-lte-elite-475cx.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/compaq-lte-elite-475cx.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./compaq-lte-elite-475cx.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 10:21:28 -0400</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Real Genius
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Earlier this week, we lost another great actor in Val Kilmer. Most people will
 always think of Iceman from Top Gun when they think of him, or Batman, but to me
 he will always be Chris Knight from <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0089886/">
 Real Genius</a>. So to honor him in my own way, I continued my rewatch of my old
 favorites with this gem.</p>

<p>Even though laser technotogy has come a long way since the mid-80's, this movie
 played just as well today as it did 40 years ago. I'm guessing people not interested
 in such technology probably now about the same amount about lasers now as they did
 back then, and because the laser was just a prop for the character-driven story, the
 movie aged well.</p>

<p>If you've never seen it, you owe it to yourself to check it out. It's one of my
 favorite movies of all time, and some of Val Kilmer's best work.</p>


<p>Tags: <a href='tag_movies.html'>movies</a>, <a href='tag_real-genius.html'>real-genius</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/real-genius.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/real-genius.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./real-genius.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 07:59:27 -0400</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
The Matrix: Ressurections
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Wrapped my rewatch with <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt10838180/">The 
 Matrix: Ressurections</a> last night, and I barely made it through it. I kept
 finding myself distracted and reaching for my phone to play a round of Suduku
 or something to keep me entertained.</p>

<p>It wasn't bad, per-se, but I think it brings the problems with all the sequels
 to the foreground. They all focused way too much on the love story between Neo
 and Trinity, and also went all-in on the action. While I liked the concept, which 
 went back to bending reality and  asking what was real and what wasn't, but instead
 of being subtle about it, it kept hitting us over the head with it. It wasn't
 taking us on a journey, it was preaching at us. And that was even worse than
 focusing on the wrong things. ;)</p>

<p>There is another sequel in the works. I hope they drop the love story. I hope
 they use action well, like in the first one, and don't rely on it too much like
 they did with all the sequels. I hope they find a good concept and take us on a
 journey instead of bludgeoning us with it. Time will tell.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_movies.html'>movies</a>, <a href='tag_matrix.html'>matrix</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/the-matrix-ressurections.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/the-matrix-ressurections.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./the-matrix-ressurections.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 08:33:26 -0400</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
The Matrix: Revolutions
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>We finally made it to <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0242653/">Revolutions</a>,
 that unsatistfying end to the original Matrix trilogy. I no longer feel like
 <a href="the-matrix-reloaded.html">Reloaded</a> ruined it, and it's not a <b>bad</b>
 movie. It just wasn't great. I'm glad I finally rewatched it.</p>

<p>Overall, the entire trilogy holds up fairly well. The original was mind-blowing
 when it came out and is still a great film. The other two are simultaniously
 better and worse than I remembered them. The second one was too long and the ending
 just wasn't very satisfying, which is probably why they eventually made the new one,
 <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt10838180/">The Matrix: Cash Grab</a>, errr... 
 <b>Resurrections</b>. I'll be wrapping up with that next, even though it took me
 several attempts to make it through it the first time.</p>
 
<p>Tags: <a href='tag_movies.html'>movies</a>, <a href='tag_matrix.html'>matrix</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/the-matrix-revolutions.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/the-matrix-revolutions.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./the-matrix-revolutions.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 08:14:27 -0400</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
The Animatrix
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>The rewatch continues with <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0328832/">The 
 Animatrix</a>. It's harder to judge this one, as it's the only animated one in the
 series, and is also a bunch of different shorts taking place at vaious different
 times in the chonology. This is why I am doing these in release order instead of
 chronologically.</p>

<p>Some of the shorts are prequels, some take place between the movies, and some
 have no specific timeframe and could take place at any time before, during, or
 after the original trilogy. They are considered canon, though, so I included them
 in the rewatch.</p>

<p>I  amd not a huge anime fan, but I remember enjoying these when they came out,
 and I still enjoyed them on this rewatch. The styles they're done in varies, and
 I quite enjoyed the different ways they were animated. The range from more traditional
 anime to near-realistic, almost uncanny valley, type of animation. And the stories
 really flesh out the universe a bit, which gives the entire series much more depth.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_movies.html'>movies</a>, <a href='tag_the-matrix.html'>the-matrix</a>, <a href='tag_matrix.html'>matrix</a>, <a href='tag_animatrix.html'>animatrix</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/the-animatrix.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/the-animatrix.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./the-animatrix.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 09:08:01 -0400</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
The Matrix: Reloaded
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I decided to not skip anything in my rewatch of <a href="/the-matrix.html">The
 Matrix</a>, and am watching them in release order, so that meants I did wind up
 watching <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0234215/">Reloaded</a> last night.</p>

<p>I think this is the first time I've rewatched it since it came out. As previously
 mentioned, I had originally thought that the series was stronger without it, and
 that it someone ruined <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0242653/">Revolutions</a>.
 While still not my favorite movie, I didn't find it nearly as bad as I did way
 back when I originally watched it. There are a few scenes which probably should
 have never made it past the cutting room, but overall it was better than I remembered.</p>

<p>Because I am going in release order, <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0328832/">The
 Animatrix</a> is next.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_movies.html'>movies</a>, <a href='tag_matrix.html'>matrix</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/the-matrix-reloaded.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/the-matrix-reloaded.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./the-matrix-reloaded.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 10:12:11 -0400</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
The Matrix
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Continuing on my binge of older movies, I just finished the first of <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0133093/">The Matrix</a>
 trilogy, and I am suprised at how well it holds up.</p>

<p>I remember when this one first came out. My wife an I watched a *lot* of movies
 back then. We had gone to a packed cinema on a Friday or Saturday evening and took
 her brother and parents with us. The showing was nearly sold out, and we wound up
 with crappy seats (way too close and way too off from the center of the screen) for
 a movie none of us had actually heard of. And then the lights went down and the
 movie started, and all the complaining about being too crowded and crappy seats
 suddenly stopped.</p>

<p>As I mentioned, the original held up extremely well. I did not like the second
 film in the series, and always felt like <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0242653/">
 Revolutions</a> would have been much better if Reloaded had never happened, so I don't know
 whether to skip <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0234215/">Reloaded</a> and go
 straight to <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0328832/">The Animatrix</a> or not.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_movies.html'>movies</a>, <a href='tag_matrix.html'>matrix</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/the-matrix.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/the-matrix.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./the-matrix.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 17:27:20 -0400</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Airheads
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>This one is a bit newer than <a href="/the-blues-brothers.html">The Blues Brothers</a>,
 and I'm not a huge fan of Adam Sandler, but <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0109068/">Airheads</a>
 was another great music comedy that I just finished a rewatch of. Definitely going in my rotation for
 fairly regular rewatch.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_movies.html'>movies</a>, <a href='tag_comedy.html'>comedy</a>, <a href='tag_airheads.html'>airheads</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/airheads.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/airheads.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./airheads.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 12:05:12 -0400</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
The Blues Brothers
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>Many times, when I watch a movie that I haven't seen in a long time, it triggers
 a flood of memories. Not so with this one, but I enjoyed every minute of the extended
 cut of <a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0080455/">The Blues Brothers</a>. This
 is such an amazing movie, even 45-ish years after I first saw it, that I didn't even
 notice that is was 2 1/2 hours.</p>

<p>John Belushi was such an amazing actor who left us way too soon, but this movie is
 filled with amazing talent, from the comedic actors to the amazing musicians who lend
 their talent to the movie. There are also a ton of great cameos. Some of them are
 pretty obvious, but some of them not so much. ;) I won't spoil them for you if you
 have never noticed some of the actors and musicians (and others) who show up in a
 scene here or there, but even many of the &quot;extras&quot; were, or later became,
 famous in their own right. ;)</p>

<p>If it's been awhile since you've seen it, or especially if you've never seen it
 before, you owe it to yourself to watch it as soon as you have the time.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_movies.html'>movies</a>, <a href='tag_classics.html'>classics</a>, <a href='tag_the-blues-brothers.html'>the-blues-brothers</a>, <a href='tag_comedy.html'>comedy</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/the-blues-brothers.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/the-blues-brothers.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./the-blues-brothers.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 21:37:16 -0400</pubDate></item>
<item><title>
Some Links
</title><description><![CDATA[

<p>I've added a page to share some <a href="/links.html">links</a> for sites I enjoy, some of them small and some not. I started when a friend mentioned his wife's page about 
 <a href="https://ominouswoosh.neocities.org/">Twin Peaks</a>, and I will add sites as I go. Some of the links will be to people I know, or close to someone I know, and some
 will just be stuff I've stumbled across, probably via a <a href="http://webring.dinhe.net/random">Random</a> <a href="http://wiby.me/surprise/">button</a> for one of the
 <a href="http://geekring.net/site/NUMBER/random">Webrings</a> I've joined, <a href="https://neustadt.fr/essays/the-small-web/">surfing the web the way it was meant to be surfed</a>.</p>

<p>Tags: <a href='tag_website.html'>website</a>, <a href='tag_links.html'>links</a>, <a href='tag_friends.html'>friends</a></p>
<!-- text end -->
<p id='twitter'><a href="http://www.nitemarecafe.com/some-links.html#disqus_thread">Comments?</a> &nbsp;
</p>
]]></description><link>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/some-links.html</link>
<guid>http://www.nitemarecafe.com/./some-links.html</guid>
<dc:creator>Wintermute</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 20:46:43 -0500</pubDate></item>
</channel></rss>
